Now, we'll call the regular scheduled meeting of the Minority Council for December 6, 2021.
To public input, I'm scheduled personal appearances. We have Mr. Rebecca Jim.
But there's an issue that's come up that I think you would like to ask citizens in the community to do.
And that would be to individually as an in your own capacity.
Right comments to FEMA, up and after the new, they have a request for information for public input,
on the revising and the national flood insurance program.
So it can be helpful for communities that are going to be flooding.
We notice that it happens. And so this, they haven't updated their standards.
I've made 50 years. And the way behind, and I think, we have so many people that have experienced flooding here.
What they say in their comment in the instructions is, you can sign on a lot of form letters or whatever.
But they don't count as much as one heartfelt letter from any individual that's been flooded.
The other thing that you can comment on is how a flood by management standards can be changed to make communities safer.
And some of this is just basic, basic ideas. And one would be, don't build workflows.
And there are several recommendations that are being made throughout the country, by many other communities.
They're asking for a provision in a construction in 100 youthful places.
And also to require no, and I think you've heard from my, maybe, every day, that critical infrastructure not be put in five people.
And so they're trying to establish this as a basis to go on into the future.
And it's not opportunity for citizens and people in your family to make a comment that can change the history for the rest of the citizens that follow us in the next.
generations. So I've got some copies and I'll leave them here, and there's a way that
you submit copies, comments, and there's a website. It's very simple you can type in
your message, but they really wanted to be a based on what we're talking about.
Don't just have a fit about something, but direct it toward these things that we really need
to have done. We need to have the rules changed. We need to make sure that if someone
is selling property, that the buyer knows that it's a flood risk. That should be a
no brainer, but until it's really in the rules, we gotta have to have it. And so we need
to make a flood insurance fair and to protect the flooding and the ecosystem that we live
around. So on that note, I've got these copies, and then I do have copies of this particular
flood map that I'll leave out here for them. It has a darker blue as the flood wipe
where we've heard floods, and then the wire blue is the 100-year flood link, and then the goal is
the 500-year floodplain. This little section here is where that mud that moved out. And so that would
be something that anyone could look at to see if we're writing comments, how to see if we look
in our lives. And what can we do about it? We can do something now. We can make comments and we'll
protect the future and future communities all over the country. And the last thing I'd like to
say is, thank you. We celebrate with the Army Corps of Engineers, asking GRDA to come in and
clean up the dams that were built for long time. And that was done last Thursday. And we're really
really pleased with thankful for it. However, you've helped make that happen and to protect the community
that way. Thank you. Number three, consent and agenda staff recommends we approve items four and five.
Second. Five. Babes. Sevenburg. Five. Parker. Six budget amendments. Number 22,
dash 13, Jan. 5, general and administrative. And 2014, demo, general and administrative.
Mr. Michael. Normal budget amendments. The 20.
in 2013, if my my senior center, they did their end of the year, they go live in, they did not submit, they read the request that they could have submitted.
They've had some turnover there, Mr. Buff Island has taken over it, and when they do their end of the year, there's a lot of that they didn't.
Docs did receive one of their payments for $1,000, maybe some of the two of their $3,000 payments for each quote.
However, all their documentation to receive those payments was submitted, so therefore we're asking it later to amend the budget to go ahead and pay them for the allotments that they should have received last year, have they requested.
In 2014, we're just using our carryover money from last year to let them do the demos, but the main development of the demos that they need to do, they're just spending the money that they already, they carry out from last year.
It's made approval to do this business.
Any questions or concerns of all that for my?
I'll make motion to approve.
All psychos.
Hi.
Thank you.
Seven.
Remember, I've understand you.
In my view.
For use of Joe Pollock Sports Complex, facility for Sports and Recreation Activities of Modipuppet School.
Just a minute.
Please.
The background on this is the MOU that we do this year.
We feel that this MOU covers and protects the represented parties involved.
Semi-U provides a agreement with the city and the MIMA Public School.
To use Joe Pollock Sports Complex, facility without rental fees, so they continue to provide activities for residents and enhanced quality of life for MIMA.
If you're unfamiliar with the MOU, we have one for all of our Sports Complex with the softball and the baseball.
This one is with the high school to kind of sum it up.
We take care of the outside of the facility.
They take care of the inside of what that is.
They mow the yard.
They mow the field.
They take care of the prepped field.
The dirt board can provide the basis.
It's meaning.
Made your.
Break each of like water lines or a letter.
What if the city steps in and takes that?
It's been a really good.
The U.S. worked out really well for most sides.
Is this what those MOU use when you only do for a year?
Yes.
I'll make it most.
Has it been through your committee count been approved it was you know the last meeting we had just it was this one with the sports ones
Yes, this one
I thought it yeah, I used to be a neck man and it was
It was wrong for the last meeting. Okay, I'll make a motion to approve
Second
Hi
Denver
Hey 22 22 holiday schedule. Are they call the days were closed?
Wow, that's an impressive lid
You're saying
We track pretty closely with the federal reserve
Somebody that came to work in the state isn't this a shot come
I'll make a motion to approve
Hi
9 20 22 meeting schedule
I'll make a motion to approve
sugar
Resolution CC 2021 to our 16
Confidication
codification
My uncle on the code of ornces include supplement the 14 so twice a year
Unicode
puts out a
Loose leaf
Dendom of the ordinances that we've changed since the last time they put it out
We're required by law to do that to get it to the law library at the county courthouse
It just keeps us current with the law if we if we did not do that then we have to
have to go through a process of rewriting our entire ordinance as every ten years, which would
be an impossibility for us to do, and we could not assess any fines in court.
Motion to approve.
Davis, don't hold me.
It's some burden.
Aye.
I love an appointment at Bo Reese in Todd Klein, as the 2022 representatives to grant Gateway
Board of Directors for a one-year turn, beginning February 2022.
Motion.
Second.
All right.
Davis.
Aye.
Summer.
Parker.
Aye.
Twelve.
A lot of engagement with a full-down financial services.
There's a 1.22 audit for electric water waste water and solid waste, rate
study, and non-hrate fee study.
This one we make motion to have no action.
Correct.
Somebody.
If we need that.
We don't need it.
Mm-hmm.
To get a way to do it.
No confusion.
Second.
Fair enough.
Aye.
So full-down.
Send-berg.
Aye.
Parker.
13 agreement for Oklahoma Community Council.
We'll talk about it grant for spring 2022 and offer us a major signature.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Anything.
How are you?
We twice a year, right, grant to the Oklahoma Community Council.
And this just provides each time a thousand dollars.
They send a set of books.
And everybody that participates gives a copy of the book, Rae.
Again, man, we have professors from different universities that come in and talk about
the book.
And so it's like a once in my book discussion.
It doesn't cost us anything other than we do ship the books back.
It's mostly in decline.
It's just the hours to write the grant into, to put those studies together and everything.
So it's just a good free of discussion for the community.
Thank you.
Parker?
Aye.
24 hundred sixties.
Fourteen.
Thank you, merchant.
Mayors and想 nation appoint Cotty Talks.
And the city, zoning and planning commission.
Motion.
Second?
High.
Symbol.
All four.
Five.
Fifteen is 70 Businessda Bans mind VII, area residents posting of this agenda.
16 staff reports.
17 Mayor and Council's Community in the House of Lords.
You got something to say?
I'm sorry.
I'll wait.
I'll do that.
You'll be enough for me to do that.
No.
You bring it.
I'll do it.
We are a town of 13,000, 300 people.
And the only consistent observation that I receive out of about town,
and I'm not out very much and probably don't see very many,
but it's how slow we are.
That's something.
And one of the benefits I would think,
to be in a town of 13,300,
was that would be that we would be a little more nimble.
Somehow, some way.
Something less than an act of Congress to get something done.
Notice, want to be on record is.
I am going to be a persistent and constant aggravation
to anyone that's not on board with that,
or if it's not going to continue to sit in a seat,
because we got to get faster.
That's all.
I agree.
I hear the same stuff.
And it's frustrating.
I mean, I know,
those of you that work in government are probably used to it.
That's the, or maybe this.
We're not used to it.
And it's aggravating.
Because we want to get something done.
And there's a bunch of hoops that we've got to jump through.
That we're not used to.
And I don't fit the hoop very well.
So what I was going to say is,
I was going to talk about the Christmas parade.
Wow.
It was a given.
I had fun.
It was very enjoyable.
You know, the tree lighting ceremony.
That we did Saturday night.
But when I thought that up on in this truck,
I'm back from downstream.
On Wednesday.
And the way to feed phone calls and pull it off.
But, um, and Tyler and his crew did a great job with the tree.
And it looked good.
They were really good.
Um,
It lit up nice.
We were kind of worried about when both of the button went in a light.
But it did.
But I like lights.
Lots of lights.
So can we add more to the tree next year?
It looked good.
But I like more.
I'll just try to find a tree.
So be a 12 year study to get that.
But I've heard a lot of reaction from
from people in town that I've told me it was the best parade we've had in a long time.
So that was great.
That was good to hear.
And Christmas.
I love Christmas time.
So I think we should focus to make that bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger.
I know your crew probably thinks I'm going to gosh.
But they did a good job.
It seemed like it was too much longer than it was last year.
Driving my little boat down Main Street, I really, there was more people this year than
I've seen at a long time that come out for the parade.
You're both looking a lot smaller than everybody else.
Probably was a little bit.
But there was a lot of turnout.
It was big.
It was nice.
It was a good feeling.
No matter what it was perfect.
Yeah, there was a lot of people.
The kids, the kids' faces, the smiles, the excitement, it was fun.
It was a good time.
So I appreciate everybody that put the work in.
I know your guys not only put up the tree and decorate the tree and hung all the stuff on the poles,
but then they had their own float too.
So I appreciate your guys and their effort they put in to make it special.
Yeah, I mean, there's our elf suit just big.
I mean, I think that's Santa.
I think that's Santa.
We're one of the rain beers.
But I'll dress up a little around here.
Maybe to pile on that a little bit, Mayor.
I mean, this, when me and my family talked about moving back to Miami, this is the kind of thing that drew us here.
Growing up in Miami in the memories of our sidewalk cells and our parades and our homecomings.
And these are the things I wanted my kids, my adult children and my grandkids to experience.
And to get to come to Miami's Christmas parade and have the tree lighting.
And I had my two grand babies there with me.
That was just an incredible memory of everything I wanted it to be.
And so I think these things are, they're important for those of us that live here.
I think it's important for the culture of our community.
And I think that's what makes Miami strong and Miami grow and makes us a community.
Just coming together and doing those things and it makes us stand out.
So I'm very proud of what we did and in Tyler's group did an amazing job.
And you know, you talk about doing more and then sweating it.
Those guys love Christmas.
They really do.
I mean, they're out there, they're float, they built their float, they were out there.
And your costume was running around and having a ball.
And I sincerely appreciate all that they did.
And the tree did light up, we hit the button.
But it was great.
So I think we can only do more of the bigger and better and have more fun.
And just so I ran out as we designed the last section of the main design.
The ViPoles to evolve the Christmas.
The big Christmas.
That would be a lot.
The big ball.
But the thing is, for us to do this,
we got to start in January to be able to get the stuff.
We got to keep that in mind. Unfortunately, you got to order things in January to get to them by the same day.
So if we want to do more, we've got to do it fast.
What happened to them big balls that we used to have?
They were rooting in the flood.
I know that last time.
I heard through the great vine at Tyler would put however many lights we wanted downtown as long as we approved the budget for it.
It's barely true.
So can you get a strike?
Can you get a strike?
No, another thing I was going to say about the Chris sprayed that Kevin was there in his boat.
The way he also drove a vehicle in it.
I saw a brand new step which I didn't know I did where he was at.
I guess.
Yeah, he drove one.
David and myself were there both there.
I see you there, man.
It's better.
I saw Tyler, several other department heads.
Amanda, HT, HT was driving one of the motorcycles in there.
So it was a good showing.
So it was great.
Anybody else for the council?
Well, okay.
18.
So you managed communications.
So before we wrap up tonight, one of the things that I wanted to kind of go on a record and maybe explain to the council.
Back on November 15th, we had had a presenter and had some discussion regarding the dollar general annexation and whether or not there were some specific.
Inspections of things that were done by the city.
And although I wasn't here during that time, I did circle back and get more intel on exactly what we had to do.
Technically done outside of the city limits.
However, because this dollar general at the time it was being built, it was known it was going to use city utilities.
So all of the typical inspections done for life safety, power water, all of those things were absolutely done during the construction of the building.
As well as our floodplain management, we're closely with the county to ensure that all of the correct permitting and sign-offs were done with
WRB, the Oklahoma Water Resource Board and FEMA.
And to that degree, that's ultimately what kind of held up the program so long because of obtaining that proper certification identified some of the issues that they had modified their design.
So they had to go back and redo some design engineering before they did construction.
But I did want to clarify that on the record that there were significant and all the appropriate certifications for time.
But I've answered a lot of the questions you have that went into.
Yes.
Which is always good for someone to bring with us.
that we're doing, probably should be doing.
And that's all the comments I had tonight.
All right.
19.
This meeting will now be continued.
It counts chambers.
I'm reading the staff right for the purpose of the executive session.
But you guys have a forum.
All right.
We're ready.
I'm serious.
I'm moving on.
They're coming in right now.
Thanks a lot.
Before we can be in this meeting,
I got to clear out of the executive session.
We already did that.
Okay.
So number 22.
Action.
For turn on order please.
FOP.
Logs.
121.
22.
Contract.
I'll take a motion to approve.
Aye.
Sunder.
David.
Aye.
Number 23.
Gentlemen.
Sunder.